Breno Silva | Senior Software Engineer

Location: Utrecht, Netherlands | **Email**: brenophp@gmail.com | **Phone**: +31 64 301 2030

Linkedin: Link | Github: Link | Portfolio: Link.

ABOUT ME

I'm a Software Engineer seasoned in DevOps, Web Development, and Machine Learning. Currently residing in Utrecht, the Netherlands, my roots are in the small town of Alegre, Brazil. I'm proud to have launched 'InfrAÇÕES', a mobile app that garnered over 100k users. My diverse experiences also include serving as a police officer for five years. A lifelong learner and father of an amazing girl, my journey in coding began at the age of 11 and continues passionately to this day.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

June 2023 - Present | Senior Software Engineer at Bol.com, Netherlands

Working inside the SecOps team. My goal is to simplify and improve software related processes:

- > Leading the development and implementation of comprehensive vulnerability scanners, enhancing the security posture across the company's landscape.
- > Leading improvements in DevOps practices, significantly enhancing the infrastructure for the team's projects.
- > Conducted a team's assessment to raise awareness and help the leadership understand and prioritize pain points.

June 2021 - June 2023 | Senior Machine Learning Engineer at Wildlife Studios, Brazil

Technically leading a task force of 4 engineers responding directly to a Director:

- > Migration of 100+ Airflow DAGs from Airflow 1 to Airflow 2. Helping the company eliminate a long overdue technical debt.
- > Lead a short-term squad to map all Databricks and AWS costs. All costs were made available on a table and a dashboard that could be consumed to every team.
- > With the costs mapped, I used that information to find cost opportunities across the entire landscape, which helped the company save more than USD 500 thousand dollars per year.

Working inside the LTV modeling squad:

- > Enhanced pipeline resilience and fault-tolerance, safeguarding against financial losses through fallback mechanisms.
- > Simplified the ML pipelines, delivering the LTV predictions faster (from 90 to 20 minutes).
- > Migrated pipelines intermediate data from Parquet/ORC to Delta Tables, delivering faster to query and easier to debug pipelines.

March 2020 - June 2021 | Data Scientist at Itaú Unibanco, Brazil

Working inside the customer relationship management analytics team:

- > Developed a feature store for customer variables, accelerating analysis and machine learning model development cycle.
- > Lead the development of a machine learning model to predict non-client enterprise lifetime value.

June 2019 - March 2020 | Software Engineer Consultant at IBM, Brazil

Working inside the IBM analytics consultancy team for the mining company Vale:

- > Developed a MLOps platform for model training, model storage, and model deployment.
- > Implemented a web platform for mine topography interaction with real-time data, optimizing the previous weekly generated view process.

October 2014 - March 2019 | Software Engineer at NerdES, Brazil

Leading the development of software projects for the company clients:

- > Developed a web platform and mobile application for a company that manages funds for graduates. The platform offered features like: integration with payment providers, charts and students' invoices processing.
- > Developed a web platform and mobile application for a company that helps students prepare for college admission exams. The platform offered features like: study calendars, quiz sections, and class video streaming.

EDUCATION

Universidade Federal do Espírito Santo, Brazil

Graduated in Bachelor of Science in Computer Science:

- > Trained GANs to develop copycat attacks against black box DNNs for my final thesis (repository).
- > Worked as T.A. for an Android Development class.

OPEN SOURCE

Main Contributions

Gitlab CLI (golang): feat: add --web flag to ci command and fix: duplicated aliases.

Streamlit (python and react): fix: dataframe wrong text-alignment for string columns and fix: how-to-use example code.

Github CLI (golang): docs: improve command description.

My Packages

Mix.nvim (25 stars): A Mix Wrapper for Neovim.